#Encodergasm Presents
～
（フェイ）なっ！ ああ あんた
いつから そこに？
S-Since when were you...
Water sploosh...
（エド）みじゅ ざー
え？ 知ってるの？ これ
You know this?
I think I know, I don't think I know.
知ってるような　知らないような
I don't think I know that I know.
知ってるのを知らないような
知らないのに知ってるような
I think I know even though I don't think I know...
どっちなの？
Which is it?!
（寝息）
こら！
Hey!
Hey Spike, where the hell are we?!
（ジェット）おい スパイク
ここは どこだ？
Isn't it Earth?
（スパイク）地球だろ
Earth?!
（ジェット）地球？
Hey, this ship was headed for Mars!
おい 火星に
向かってたはずの船が―
Why the hell are we on Earth all of a sudden?!
どうして いきなり
地球にいるんだよ？
（スパイク）さあ
Dunno.
（ジェット）
ああ くそ 冗談じゃねえ
Shit, this isn't funny.
While we're wasting time, our fugitive...!
こんなことしてる間に
せっかくの首が
久々の大物だってのに
大体 何でまた こんなとこ…
It was the first big one in a while.
In any case why the hell are we on...?
（スパイク）ジェット
Jet.
The women are gone.
（スパイク）女どもがいない
（ジェット）ああん？
（フェイ）いい？
Listen, if you lead me to that "water sploosh" place...
ちゃんと その“みじゅ ざー”の
ある所に案内してれたら―
...l'll give you something good.
いいものあげる
Good thing?  What?
（エド）いいもの 何？
Something very, tremendously, wonderfully good.
ものすごく とっても
素晴らしく いいものよ
えへへ
Something very, tremendously, wonderfully good!
ものすごーく とーっても
すーばらしく いいものー
HOT!
（アップルデリー）
あちーい！ エホッ
Hot!  Hot!  Hot!  Hot!
あち あち あちー！
～
This!
（エド）これー
Water sploosh!
水 じゃー　アハハハハ
（フェイ）
まあ あんたを当てにした
私が間違ってたわ
I knew I shouldn't have trusted you.
あ エド 見っけ
Hey, I found Ed!
ほあ？ エド 見っけられっけ？
Ed has been found?
何？ 知り合い？
What, you know them?
（少年１）さんじゅうごてん
よんじゅうはってんご…
35 point 38 point 0, 35 point 48 point 1, 35 point 48 point 2...
（少年２）これ～
これ これ これ
This!
This, this, this!
ねえ 爪ちょうだい？
Hey, can I have your nails?
Nails?
爪？
集めてんの　ちょうだい
I'm collecting them!
Can I, please?
- 35 point 52 point 3, 35 point...
- Just the pinky one will do!
小指のでいいから
This, this!
What are you guys?!
Come on... can I have it?  Please?
何なの？ あんたたち
（クララ）こーらー！
HEY!
（子供たち）うぇっ わあああ
うっ…
あっ！ エド
ED?!
エヘヘヘ
まさか
Is that really you...  Ed?
エドなのか？
（クララ）すまなかったねえ
I'm sorry about that.
子供に言うこと聞かせるには
あれが一番なんだ
That's the best way to make the kids listen.
（フェイ）いいのよ
It's all right.
Is Ed from this place?
エドって ここの子なの？
（クララ）５年ほど前
ふらっと迷い込んできてな
She wandered in about five years ago.
Before I knew it, she was eating with us as if it had always been that way.
気が付いたら
当たり前の顔して飯 食ってたんだ
で ３年ほど前
ふらっといなくなった
And about three years ago, she wandered away.
まるで猫か何かみたいにね
As if she was a cat or something.
今頃 どこで どうしているのかって
思ってたんだけど―
I was wondering how she was doing nowadays...
いきなり現れるなんてね
...but I didn't think she would suddenly appear.
All right, it's time to eat!
よし！ 飯にするぞ
（子供たち）わあああ！
（せきばらい）
天にまします われらの父よ…
以下省略
Dear Lord up in the heavens...
Never mind the rest.  Let's eat!
いただきます！
Let's eat!
（子供たち）いただきまーす！
（フェイ）
あっ 私 もう行かないと
I have to get going now...
なんだい　まだ いいだろ？
What, you can stay longer, right?
（フェイ）
ちょっと探し物があって
I'm actually looking for something...
エドが知ってるよ
Ed knows where it is.
（フェイ）えっ？
We just came here for food.
ここには ちょっと
ご飯 食べに来てただけなの
く… あんたね
You...
You have to gimme something good!
（エド）ちゃーんと いいもの
ちょうだいねー
Oh yeah, Ed.
そうだ エド
There's something good in the desk drawer over there.
そこの机
引き出しに いいもんが入ってる
Something good?
いいもの？
Go get it.
取ってきな
Something good!
いいものだー
Inside that drawer.
（クララ）そこの引き出しの中だ
（エド）うーん
にゃ？
（クララ）それじゃなくて
Not that.
にゃにゃ
Yeah, that.  Open it!
（クララ）そう それだ
開けてみな
にゃー？
Her father.
父親だ
えっ 誰の？
WHOSE?
He came looking for Ed about 2 months ago.
（クララ）ほんの２か月ほど前
エドを捜しに来たんだよ
He said he forgot that he had put her in an orphanage...
託児所に預けといたのを
忘れてたんだとさ
それから７年―
...and that he had been looking for 7 years, hopping around the world.
あちこち転々としながら
捜してるって言ってた
I hope she will be able to meet him.
会えるといいんだけどね
人間 絆ってのは大事にしないと
People have to cherish what ties they have.
Yeah!
イエイ
Are you...  Faye?
（サリー）あなた フェイ？
Impossible...
うそ
Really?
（サリー）本当に？
（フェイ）あっ
It's me, Sally Yung!
（サリー）私よ サリー･ユー
I was in your high school graduating class!
ハイスクールのときの同級の
（サリーのせき）
あ 大丈夫？
Are you all right?
ふー びっくりしたわ
幽霊かと思った
I was really surprised.
I thought you were a ghost.  You look just like back then.
昔のままなんだもの
ほら 未練のある場所に
出るって言うでしょ
You know, they say ghosts appear in places where they have regrets.
Oh, yeah, I remember now.
そうそう 思い出したわ
You were put in cold sleep after that accident.
あのときの事故で
コールドスリープしてたのよね
And that's why you look like back then...
それで昔のまんまで
（フェイ）事故？
Accident?
You don't remember, Faye?
（サリー）フェイ 覚えてないの？
I-I...
私…
Grandma!
おばあちゃーん！
Grandma, we gotta go back now.
おばあちゃん もう戻らなきゃ
（サリー）まあ もうそんな時間？
Is it that time already?
Do you know who this is?
この人 誰だか分かる？
I bet you don't know.  Actually, she's...
分からないでしょ？
実は彼女はね
幽霊なのよ
...a ghost.
（２人）えっ？
フッ
さよなら　元気で
Good-bye.  Take care.
～
Hey, you guys!
（ジェット）あ お前ら！
勝手に針路 変えやがって
What's with this course change without asking?!
Our plans have all been screwed because of it!
おかげで こっちの予定は
狂いっぱなしだ
I don't appreciate you doing things on your own!
勝手なことされちゃ 困るんだよ
とってもいいもの 嗅ぐ？
You want to smell something really good?
What's with them?
（ジェット）全く あいつら
勝手に こそこそ何やってんだ？
What are they being so secretive about?
Leave them alone.
ほっとけよ
腹の減りすぎかもしれんな
Maybe they're too hungry for their own good.
人間 食うもん食わなきゃ
おかしくもなるってもんだ
Humans go insane if they don't eat food.
5000万か
50 million?
（ジェット）うん？
I see... pretty big.
おおー 大物だな
アップルデリー･シニズ･
ヘサップ･リュトフェンか
Appledelhi Siniz Hesap Lutfen.
（アップルデリー）
君も吸うかね？ マッケンロー君
Would you like one, Mackenroe?
That's Macintire.
（マッケンタイア）
マッケンタイアです
結構です アップルデリーさん
No thank you, Mr.  Appledelhi.
You sure?  Eggs are good.
（アップルデリー）
そうかね　卵はいいぞ
As they say, power and charge.  That's what's important, Macintosh.
いわゆるパワーアンドチャージ
それがインポータントなんだ
マッキントッシュ君
That's Macintire.
マッケンタイアです
Why is it that you can't ever remember your assistant's name?
どうして いつまでたっても―
助手の名前を
覚えてくれないんですか？
うん？ へっ
細かいことは気にせんことだ
Hm, don't worry about the small things in life.
ハッハッハッハ
うん？
Hurry, Macky-Mike!
急げ！ マッキンマック君
That's Macintire!
マッケンタイアです！
（フェイ）あっ
（スパイク）うわっ
何だよ 危ねえな
Watch where you're going!
あっ あ あ…
あっ あ…
Hey?
（スパイク）おい
ごめん
Sorry...
“ごめん”？
Sorry?
あ…
I-I...
私…
行かなきゃ
I have to go.
Going out?  Where are you going?
（エド）お出掛けさーん
（フェイ）うっ
どこ行くの？
I finally remembered where I belong.
自分の居場所 思い出したの
居場所？
Where you belong?
あんたも
待ってる人がいるんだから…
You have someone waiting for you, too.  You have somewhere you belong.
居場所があるんだから
探して行くといいわ
You should go look for it, too.
（エド）うん？
That's the best thing, you know...
それが―
一番いいものなんだから
This one is a piece of cake.
（ジェット）今回は楽勝だぞ
5000万は もうすぐ そこだ
50 million is right there!
肉入りのすき焼きでも食やあ
あいつらも…
If they can eat sukiyaki filled with meat, then they...
Faye went out.
フェイなら出てったぜ
Again?
またか？ おい 今度はどこへ？
Where the hell did she go this time?
A woman's heart and the skies of Ganymede, was it?
女心とガニメデの空ってやつか
You're Appledelhi?
（ジェット）アップルデリーだな？
Can you come along with us?
一緒に来てもらおうか
Cooperate with us if you don't wanna get hurt.
ケガしたくなかったら
おとなしくしてくれ
Who are you guys?  Don't interrupt our work!
何だ？ あんたたち
仕事の邪魔しないでくれ
Work?
仕事？
What does this Earth need to regain a peaceful peace?
混乱が支配する この地球で―
われわれがピース的な平和と
ノン混乱を取り戻すには―
This Earth of wild chaos!  Is it the cosmos?
何が必要だと思う？
（スパイク）はあ？
That is a map!  A map!
それはマップ　地図だ
Yes, happiness comes in the form of a map!
そう 幸せは
地図に乗ってやってくるのだ
僕たちは この地球を救うために
地図を作っているんです
We are creating maps to save the Earth!
地図ったってえな
A map?
But, meteors fall often and change the landscape.
ここじゃ しょっちゅう
隕石が降ってきて―
地形が変わってるぞ
That's why we're globetrotting.  We're chasing after every meteor!
（アップルデリー）
だから われわれは
全ての隕石を追いかけて―
地球を巡っているのだ
Until every single meteor falls onto Earth!
（マッケンタイア）
全ての隕石が地球に落ち尽くすまで
Enough with the excuses!
ご託は結構だ！
（ジェット）うおお
野郎！
You!
I wasn't expecting someone this adept.
意外とやるな
Is that you, Ed?!
エドか
That's enough!  Stop!
もういい！ 止まれ
はっ！ フランソワーズ！
Francoise!
ふふう あは
にゃー
（エド）あははー あはは
（アップルデリー）イエー ハッハ
How's that?
（アップルデリー）
そーれ そーれ それ ハハハハ
And that, and that?
（エド）にゃー　ほー
（アップルデリー）そうらー ハハ
これは父の人
This is father-person.
Father?
父って…
Your father?
父親か？
She had such a thing?
いたのか？ そんなの
これはスパイクの人とジェットの人
This is Spike-person and Jet-person.
I see.
（アップルデリー）そうか
違うよ 父　いい人だよ
No, father.  Good people.
Oh?  I see.
うん？ そうか
Thank you for taking care of my son.
息子が世話になった
うん？ 娘だったか？
Or was it daughter?
Oh well, it's all right either way.
まあ どちらでも良し
That's a token of my appreciation.
それは礼だ
Then Ed, were you the one who put the bounty on?
じゃあ エド 賞金を懸けたのも
まさか お前…
Fifty point zero, zero, zero, zero, zero, zero?
50.000000
Only 50 Woolongs?
たったの50ウーロン？
So, you wanna come with me?
どうだ？ お前も一緒に来るか？
（マッケンタイア）ああー！
（アップルデリー）うおおお
Hurry, Michael-duck!
急げー！ マイケルダック君
That's Macintire!!
マッケンタイアです！
Hey, wait!
（ジェット）おおい 待てよ！
Father!
父ー！
He's gone.
行っちゃった
（フェイの荒い息）
Hey, it's dinner time.
おい 飯だぞ
Spike, dinner.
スパイク 飯だ
（エド）
ついてきちゃ駄目だよ アイン
You can't come with me, Ein.
Ed is going someplace far, far away.
エドは 遠い遠いとこへ行くんだよ
もう戻ってこないかも
しれないんだよ
I might not be coming back.
So Ein, you should go back home.
だからアインは
おうちに帰るんだよ
Do you want to come with Ed?
エドと一緒に行きたい？
行こう アイン
Let's go, Ein!
～
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（ジェット）
どんなものにも始まりがあり
そして終わりがある
Everything has a beginning and an end.
人生は その繰り返しだ
Life is just a cycle of them.
With unwanted endings, becoming an adult is to experience the inevitable finale.
来てほしくない終わりもあるが―
避けられない終わりを
経験していくこと
それが
大人になっていくってことなんだ
It's been a fast trip for Bebop, with only two episodes left.
早いもんでビバップも
残り あと２回だが―
But make sure you pay close attention to how it ends.
その終わりを
ちゃんと見届けてくれよ
Next episode: The Real Folk Blues, Part 1.
次回「ザ･リアル･
フォークブルース（前編）」